Ralph Ellison
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Reference File, 1901-1995, n.d. (Box 179-211)
  - Biographical information
    - Davis, Angela Yvonne, 1970-1971
    - Dawson, William L. and Cecile, 1934-1936, 1963-1993, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 184)
    - Deren, Maya, 1948, n.d.
    - "D" miscellaneous, 1934-1991, n.d., (3 folders)
    - Einstein, Albert, 1955-1972
    - Eliot, T. S., 1949-1954, 1961-1966
    - Ellington, Duke, 1944-1976, 1992, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 185)
    - "E" miscellaneous, 1946-1992, n.d.
    - Faulkner, William, 1946-1993, n.d., (3 folders)
    - Fiedler, Leslie A., 1951-1964
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott, 1945-1970 (Box 186)
    - Forrest, Leon, 1972-1988, n.d.
    - "F" miscellaneous, 1945-1988, n.d., (2 folders)
    - Gandhi, Mahatma, 1946-1948, n.d.
    - Garfield, John, 1952
    - Gide, André, 1944-1951
    - "G" miscellaneous, 1944-1993, n.d., (2 folders)
    - Hearst, William Randolph, 1951
    - Hemingway, Ernest, 1935-1978, n.d., (5 folders) See also Oversize (Box 187)
    - Hersey, John, 1985-1987, n.d. (Box 188)
    - Himes, Chester B., 1945-1947, 1965, 1989, n.d.
    - Hiss, Alger See Container 182, Chambers, Whittaker
    - Holiday, Billie, 1991, n.d. See also Oversize
    - Horne, Lena, 1944-1986
    - Hughes, Langston, 1944, 1953, 1961, 1983-1988
    - Hunter-Gault, Charlayne, 1961-1970
    - Hyman, Stanley Edgar, 1946-1978, n.d., (4 folders) See also Container 189, Jackson, Shirley
    - "H" miscellaneous, 1931-1993, n.d., (3 folders) (Box 189)
    - "I" miscellaneous, 1947-1974, 1986-1989
    - Jackson, George, 1971
    - Jackson, Jesse, 1983-1989, n.d.
    - Jackson, Shirley, 1948-1965 See also Container 188, Hyman, Stanley Edgar
    - James, Harry, 1945-1972, n.d.
    - Johnson, James Weldon, 1927-1950, n.d.
    - Johnson, Lyndon B. and Lady Bird, 1963-1990, n.d. (Box 190)
    - Johnston, Alva, 1950, n.d.
    - Joyce, James, 1939-1984, n.d.
    - "J" miscellaneous, 1934, 1945-1989, n.d.
    - Kazin, Alfred, 1946-1954, 1973, n.d.
    - Kennedy, John F., 1961-1964, 1993
    - Kierkegaard, Soren, 1945-1946
    - Koestler, Arthur, 1945-1952, 1984, n.d.
    - Kostelanetz, Richard, 1968-1972, n.d.
    - "K" miscellaneous, 1947-1990, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 191)
    - Lerner, Max, 1944-1955
    - Lincoln, Abraham, 1955, n.d.
    - Long, Earl K. and Huey Pierce, 1959-1960, n.d.
    - Louis, Joe, 1936-1937, 1946-1981, n.d.
    - "L" miscellaneous, 1945-1993, n.d., (2 folders)
    - MacDonald, Dwight, 1952-1954, 1964, 1975 (Box 192)
    - Mailer, Norman, 1960-1976, n.d.
    - Malraux, André, 1934-1976, n.d., (2 folders)
    - Marquand, John P., 1952
    - Marshall, Thurgood, 1961-1991
    - Matisse, Henri, 1948-1955, 1991
    - McCarthy, Mary, 1950-1954, 1972, 1989
    - McKelway, St. Clair, 1952-1953, 1976
    - Miller, Arthur, 1944-1972, 1987
    - Mitchell, Joe, 1944, 1951-1956, 1964 (Box 193)
    - Moore, Marianne, 1946-1954, 1972
    - Morisey, A. Alexander, 1966-1972, n.d.
    - Morris, Willie, 1965-1973
    - Morrison, Toni, 1981-1994, n.d.
    - Motherwell, Robert, 1948-1976
    - "M" miscellaneous, 1934-1939, 1945-1993, n.d., (4 folders); (1 folder) (Box 194)
    - Nixon, Richard M., 1968-1975, n.d.
    - "N" miscellaneous, 1952-1989
    - "O" miscellaneous, 1943-1990
    - Parker, Charles, 1955, n.d.
    - Parks, Gordon, 1949-1990, n.d.
    - Picasso, Pablo, 1970-1993, n.d.
    - Powell, Adam Clayton, 1958-1972
    - Price, Leontyne, 1955-1966, 1982
    - "P" miscellaneous, 1939, 1953-1992, n.d., (2 folders)
    - "Q" miscellaneous, 1978, 1989 (Box 195)
    - Randolph, A. Philip, 1989, n.d.
    - Robeson, Paul, 1967-1973, n.d.
    - Robinson, Jackie, 1945-1985
    - Robinson, Sugar Ray, 1951-1952, 1989
    - Roethke, Theodore, 1963-1969, n.d.
    - Rustin, Bayard, 1970-1987
    - "R" miscellaneous, 1945-1989, n.d., (2 folders)
    - Scott, Nathan A., 1959-1969, n.d.
    - Spady, James G., 1983-1987
    - Steegmuller, Francis, 1948-1958, 1973 (Box 196)
    - Stepto, Robert B., 1975-1983, n.d.
    - Stevens, Roger L., 1976
    - Stewart, James E., 1958-1987, n.d.
    - "S" miscellaneous, 1933-1990, n.d., (3 folders)
    - "T" miscellaneous, 1947-1991, n.d. (Box 197)
    - "U" miscellaneous, 1950, 1994
    - "V" miscellaneous, 1954-1993
    - Warren, Robert Penn, 1965-1990, n.d., (2 folders)
    - Washington, Booker T., 1945, 1973, 1984, n.d.
    - Wertham, Frederic, 1946-1974, n.d.
    - Wideman, John E., 1973-1989, n.d.
    - Wilbur, Richard, 1963-1987
    - Wright, John S., 1985, n.d.
    - Wright, Richard, 1938-1969, 1977-1993, n.d., (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 198)
    - "W" miscellaneous, 1949-1990, n.d., (3 folders)
    - Young, Whitney, 1970-1971
    - "Y-Z" miscellaneous, 1941-1954, 1970-1992, n.d.
  - Black Panthers, 1969-1973, n.d. (Box 199)
  - Booksellers and publishers, 1970-1994, n.d.
  - British royal family, 1936, 1947-1956, 1972
  - Burma, 1960, 1966-1994, n.d.
  - Capote, Truman, masked ball, 1966-1967
  - Caribbean countries, 1945-1984
  - Caucus of Minority Executives in Media, 1986
  - Chicago, Ill., 1938-1940, 1951-1987, n.d.
  - China, 1948-1958, 1972, n.d.
  - Cinema, 1934-1992, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 200)
  - Circus, 1947-1949, 1970
  - Civil rights, 1958-1988
  - Colleges, schools, and universities, 1932-1992, n.d.
  - Communism, 1931-1991
  - Computers, 1982-1983, n.d.
  - Crime
    - Florida bombings, 1951-1952
    - Irwin, Walter, 1951-1952
    - Miscellany, 1931-1992, n.d.
  - Dance
    - Alvin Ailey American Dance Theater, 1969-1974
    - American Ballet Theatre, n.d.
    - Harlem Dance Foundation, 1979-1982, n.d. (Box 201)
    - Miscellany, 1949-1990, n.d.
  - Discrimination, 1940-1984, n.d.
  - Drugs and drug use, 1960-1989, n.d.
  - Education, 1940-1992, n.d., (2 folders)
  - Europe, 1938, 1945-1958, 1971, n.d. See also Oversize
  - Fashion, 1941-1969, n.d.
  - First Amendment, 1991
  - France, 1944-1994, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 202)
  - Fund-raising, 1949, 1955, 1973-1987, n.d.
  - Harlem, New York, N.Y., 1946-1991, n.d.
  - Health, 1941-1990, n.d., (3 folders)
  - Jonestown, Guyana, People's Temple, 1978-1983 (Box 203)
  - Juvenile delinquency, 1946-1959, n.d.
  - Ku Klux Klan, 1948-1993, n.d.
  - La Farge Clinic, New York, N.Y., 1946-1953, n.d.
  - Labor, 1935-1949, 1970, 1989, n.d.
  - Libraries, 1970-1991
  - Literary publications, 1936-1993, (2 folders)
  - Lynchings, 1949-1955
  - Middle East, 1962-1983
  - Military
    - African-American soldiers, 1940-1993, n.d., (2 folders)
    - Armed conflict (Box 204)
      - Civil War, U.S., 1951-1958, n.d.
      - Korean War, 1950-1958
      - Revolutionary War, American, 1950
      - Vietnam War, 1947-1982, n.d., (2 folders)
    - Nuclear weapons, 1955, 1981
  - Minority publications, 1935-1992, (2 folders)
  - Miscellany, 1944-1987, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 205)
  - Music
    - African-American influence and perspective, 1938-1991, n.d.
    - Jazz, 1950-1992, n.d., (3 folders)
    - Miscellany, 1939-1990 (Box 206)
    - Opera, 1963-1983, n.d.
    - Recorders, 1955-1958, n.d.
    - Sheet music, 1941-1959, n.d.
  - NAACP, 1974-1984
  - National Urban Fellows, 1980
  - National Urban League, 1942-1970, n.d.
  - New York, N.Y., 1947-1990, n.d., (2 folders)
  - News reporting, 1972-1985
  - Oklahoma, 1948-1990, n.d., (3 folders) (Box 207)
  - Photography, 1937-1955, 1984, n.d. See also Oversize
  - Plainfield, Mass., 1968-1978
  - Politics, 1944-1992, n.d., (2 folders)
  - Prisons (Box 208)
    - Attica, N.Y., 1971-1972
    - Miscellany, 1971-1975
  - Radicals, 1970-1975
  - Religion, 1940-1993, n.d.
  - Science, 1982-1983, n.d.
  - Segregation, 1940-1989, n.d., (3 folders)
  - Sex, 1935-1966, 1982
  - Southern United States, 1948-1990, n.d.
  - Sports (Box 209)
    - Boxing, 1938-1971, n.d.
    - Bullfighting, 1947-1953
    - Miscellany, 1936-1984, n.d.
  - Studio Museum, Harlem, New York, N.Y., 1978-1985, n.d.
  - Teachers' guides, 1973, n.d.
  - Television
    - Miscellany, 1951-1993
    - National Citizens Committee for Broadcasting, 1971
    - Public broadcasting, 1966-1975, n.d.
  - Theater, 1901, 1934-1990, n.d., (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 210)
  - Times Square, New York, N.Y., dancing doll vendors (Clifton's dolls), 1964 See also Container 143, "Brotherhood, Clifton"
  - Travel, 1943-1987
  - United States Supreme Court, 1947, 1971-1991, n.d.
  - Watergate Affair, 1972-1975, (3 folders)
  - Western civilization, 1947-1950, 1971, n.d., (2 folders)
  - Writers and writing, 1939-1995, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 211)
- Miscellany, 1904-1994, n.d. (Box 211-219)
  Appointment books and calendars, awards and citations, honorary degrees, invitations to social, cultural, and charitable events, mailing addresses, notes, printed ephemera, and memorabilia.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material and chronologically therein.
  - Addresses, 1953, n.d., (4 folders) (Box 211, Box 212)
  - Appointment calendars
    - 1944-1953, (2 folders)
    - 1957-1965, 1975-1978, 1985-1993, (4 folders) See also Oversize (Box 213)
  - Awards, citations, and honorary degrees
    - Brown University, Providence, R.I., 1979-1980
    - Chevalier de l'Ordre des Arts et des Lettres, France, 1968-1969, n.d.
    - Chicago Defender, Chicago, Ill., 1953
    - City University of New York, New York, N.Y., 1992-1993, n.d. (Box 214)
    - College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, Va., 1972 See also Oversize
    - Friends of American Writers, 1953
    - Harold Washington Literary Award, 1992, n.d.
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass., 1974, n.d. See also Container 171, Speeches, 1974
    - National Abortion Rights Action League, 1992
    - National Book Award, 1953, 1974
    - National Medal of Arts, 1985, n.d.
    - Oklahoma, 1975, 1986
    - Oklahoma Arts and Humanities Council, Oklahoma City, Okla., 1966-1967, n.d.
    - Oklahoma State University, Stillwater, Okla., 1969
    - Presidential Medal of Freedom, 1969
    - Russwurm Award, 1953
    - Rutgers University, New Brunswick, N.J., 1966
    - Top Hat Award, New Pittsburgh Courier, Pittsburgh, Pa., 1975-1976
    - Tuskegee Institute, Tuskegee, Ala., 1963
    - University of Maryland, College Park, Md., 1974, n.d. See also Oversize
    - Wake Forest University, Winston-Salem, N.C., 1974 See also Oversize
    - Wesleyan University, Middletown, Conn., 1979-1980
  - Birthday tributes, 1989 (Box 215)
  - Communist party, 1937-1942, n.d.
  - Entertaining, 1963-1968, 1988, n.d.
  - International Workers Order, 1939
  - Invitations
    - Exhibitions
      - 1943-1946, 1952-1989, (6 folders)
      - 1990-1994, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 216)
    - General
      - 1935-1979, (5 folders)
      - 1980-1994, (6 folders) (Box 217)
      - Undated, (2 folders) (Box 218)
    - Social
      - 1935, 1946-1994, (5 folders)
      - Undated (Box 219)
  - Memberships and licenses, 1954-1960, 1969, 1987, n.d.
  - Notebook covers, n.d.
  - Printed material, 1904, 1921-1955, 1968-1985, 1993, n.d., (2 folders)
  - Programs, 1932-1976, 1992, n.d., (2 folders)
  - Ration and public assistance books, 1943, n.d.
  - Receipts, 1932-1938, 1959, n.d.
  - Recipes, 1969-1976, 1990-1991, n.d.
- Closed, 1932-1994, n.d. (Box 220-231)
  Fragile material, consisting mostly of correspondence, drawings, and writings, which has been removed and replaced with photocopies.
  Organized and described according to the series and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Family Papers (Box 220)
    - Ellison, Fanny McConnell
      - Notes, n.d.
      - School papers
        - General, n.d.
        - University of Iowa, Iowa City, Iowa, fundamentals of speech, 1936, (2 folders)
      - Writings, n.d., (2 folders)
    - Ellison, Ralph
      - Correspondence
        - Bell, Ida Ellison, 1937
        - Ellison, Fanny McConnell, 1944-1945, n.d., (2 folders)
        - Ellison, Herbert M., n.d.
      - Drawings, 1932, n.d.
      - Employment
        - Works Progress Administration, Federal Writers' Project
          - Assignments, 1938-1941, n.d.
          - Miscellany, 1938-1942, n.d.
          - Reports
            - Anti-Semitism, n.d.
            - "Famous Trials," 1941
            - Folklore, ca. 1938, (2 folders)
            - History of New York, N.Y., n.d.
            - "Jews in American Theatre," ca. 1939
            - "The Negro and the War," ca. 1940, (3 folders) (Box 221)
            - "Negro Leadership," n.d.
            - "Negroes of New York"
              - Chapt. II, n.d.
              - Chapt. V, n.d.
              - Chapt. VI, n.d.
              - Chapt. VII, n.d.
              - Chapt. XVIII, 1940
              - Notes, n.d.
            - Religion and abolitionism, n.d.
  - General Correspondence
    - "A-Ai" miscellaneous, 1940, 1946-1992, n.d.
    - Bellow, Saul, 1952-1964, 1977, 1994, n.d., (2 folders)
    - Burke, Kenneth, 1945-1954, 1964-1972, 1981-1985, n.d., (3 folders) (Box 222)
    - Harrison, Hazel, 1936-1940, 1954, 1967-1969, n.d.
    - Hughes, Langston, 1936-1966, n.d.
    - Lazenberry, Joe, 1935-1939, n.d.
    - Negro Quarterly, 1940-1945, 1968, n.d., (2 folders)
    - Wright, Richard and Ellen, 1937-1953, n.d., (2 folders)
    - Unidentified, n.d.
  - Organizations File
    - National Negro Congress, 1940, n.d.
  - Writings File
    - Essays and essay collections
      - American Negro Congress, ca. 1940
      - "Camp Lost Colony," 1940
      - "A Congress Jim Crow Didn't Attend," 1940
      - Editorial comments
        - General, ca. 1937, 1970, n.d.
        - Negro Quarterly, 1942-1944, n.d., (2 folders)
      - "Harlem Is Nowhere" (1964), 1947-1948, n.d., (3 folders)
      - Hemingway, Ernest, unfinished essay, ca. 1940, (2 folders)
      - "Imprisioned in Words," 1946-1947, n.d.
      - "Let Us Consider the Harlem Crime Wave," ca. 1943
      - Miscellaneous notes, 1943, 1953-1991, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 223)
      - New American left wing writers, ca. 1935
      - "Philippine Writers Report," 1941
      - "Recent Negro Fiction" (1941), 1941, n.d., (2 folders)
      - "Richard Wright's Blues" (1945), draft fragments and notes, 1945, n.d.
      - "The Shadow and the Act" (1949), 1949-1950, n.d.
      - Shadow and Act (1964)
        - Drafts
          - "An American Dilemma: A Review," 1944, n.d.
          - Miscellaneous text, 1964-1966, n.d.
          - "Twentieth Century Fiction and the Black Mask of Humanity," ca. 1946, 1953
      - "Society, Morality, and the Novel," The Living Novel (1957), 1956-1963, n.d.
      - "Tell It Like It Is, Baby" (1965)
        - Drafts, 1965-1969, 1990, n.d., (2 folders)
        - Galleys, notes, and general material, 1965-1969, 1990, n.d.
      - "Three Southern Novels," 1944, n.d.
      - Unidentified fragments, n.d., (2 folders)
      - "The World and the Jug" (1963), notes, n.d.
    - Memoirs, draft fragments, n.d.
    - Miscellany (Box 224)
      - Notes, 1941-1988, n.d., (4 folders)
      - Plot ideas, n.d.
      - Unidentified fragments, ca. 1940, 1963 n.d., (3 folders)
    - Novels
      - Hickman novel
        - Drafts
          - Episodes
            - Bliss and Severin's mother, n.d.
            - Bliss and Sister Georgia, n.d.
            - Bliss, Body, and Meatwhistle, 1959, 1981, n.d.
            - Cliofus talks with McIntyre, n.d.
            - Hickman and Wilhite at Mister Jessie's, complete sequences, 1968, n.d.
            - Hickman and Wilhite leave the Lincoln Memorial, n.d.
            - "Hickman Reminiscing," n.d.
            - Hickman with Bliss at the hospital, n.d.
            - "McIntyre's Dream"
              - Hitching post boy, n.d.
              - Mother Strothers, n.d.
            - "Mr. Love New," n.d.
            - Mr. Love New and Severin, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 225)
            - "Prologue," n.d.
            - Severin and the shooting of the senator, n.d.
            - Unidentified pages, n.d.
        - Notes and notebooks, 1956-1989, n.d., (12 folders)
      - Invisible Man
        - Drafts
          - Episodes
            - "At Mary's," n.d.
            - "Bar Scene, El Toro," n.d.
            - "Battle Royal," n.d.
            - "Brockaway (Paint Factory)," n.d.
            - "Brotherhood," n.d., (2 folders)
            - "Campus," n.d. (Box 226)
            - "Chapel," first draft and notes, n.d.
            - "Hospital Alley Scene," also titled "Nigger, What Kinda Man Am I?" n.d.
            - "Hospital and St. Mary's" (in continuity), n.d.
            - "Hospital Scene," working copy, n.d.
            - Miscellaneous scenes, n.d.
            - "New York," first draft and notes, n.d.
            - "Perception," orginal draft titled "Eviction, Priest, Parade, Party, Bank, and Apartment," n.d.
            - "Priest Scene," n.d.
            - "Prologue," n.d.
            - "Riot," n.d.
            - "Woodridge," n.d.
          - Fragments and partial drafts, 1951, n.d., (5 folders)
          - Notes, 1945-1950, n.d., (6 folders); (7 folders) (Box 227)
        - Foreign rights and translations, 1952-1978
        - Publicity, n.d.
        - Published editions
          - New American Library of World Literature
            - 1951-1971, n.d.
          - Random House, correspondence, 1947-1969
      - Slick novel
        - Drafts
          - Episodes
            - Booker's reveries, n.d.
            - "Mister Mac" or "Tale of a Southern Road," n.d., (2 folders)
            - Slick and Booker hunting, n.d.
            - Slick and Bostic, n.d.
            - Slick and Callie at the hospital, n.d.
            - Slick and Liles, n.d.
            - Slick and Snodgrass, n.d.
          - Original typescript
            - Section I, ca. 1939
            - Section II, ca. 1939 (Box 228)
          - Miscellaneous pages, ca. 1939
          - Notes, n.d.
    - Poetry, 1935-1937, n.d.
    - Reviews
      - 1937-1946, (10 folders)
      - 1947-1964, (4 folders) (Box 229)
    - Short stories
      - "Afternoon," n.d.
      - "The Birthmark," 1940, n.d.
      - "Butler Boy and the TV Set," n.d.
      - "The Dream," 1941, n.d., (6 folders)
      - "Flying Home," 1944, 1971-1974, 1992, n.d., (2 folders)
      - "Gann Wilson," n.d. (Box 230)
      - "A Hard Time Keeping Up" (posthumous title), n.d.
      - "Hymie's Bull" (posthumous title), n.d.
      - "I Did Not Learn Their Names," ca. 1940
      - "The Initiation," n.d., (5 folders)
      - "Jake Smith," n.d.
      - "The King of the Bingo Game," 1944, 1970-1974, 1980, 1988-1992, n.d.
      - "Mister Toussan," 1941-1947, 1971, n.d.
      - "Myth Mood," ca. 1937
      - Notes, 1978-1980, 1988-1990, n.d.
      - "The Red Cross at Morriston, Swansea, S.W.," n.d.
      - "Slick Gonna Learn," 1939
      - "A Storm of Blizzard Proportions," 1944, n.d.
      - "That I Had the Wings," n.d. (Box 231)
      - Tillman and Tackhead, n.d., (3 folders)
      - Untitled, n.d., (3 folders)
    - Writings by others
      - Bone, Robert, 1972
      - Miscellaneous, 1936-1965
  - Speeches, Lectures, and Interviews
    - Lectures
      - 1945, 1 Nov., "American Negro Writing, A Problem of Identity," Bennington College, Bennington, Vt., 1945, n.d.
      - 1969, 26 Mar., lecture on Invisible Man, United States Military Academy, West Point, N.Y., 1973-1974, n.d.
    - Interviews
      - 1960, 11 May, "A Talk with Ralph Ellison," Richard G. Stern, 1960-1961, n.d.
    - Miscellaneous notes and fragments, n.d.
- Oversize, 1923-1993, n.d. (Box OV 1-OV 22)
  Oversize material consisting mostly of drawings, financial and legal records, writings, and printed material.
  Organized and described according to the series, folders, and boxes from which the items were removed.
  - Family Papers (Box OV 1)
    - Ellison, Fanny McConnell
      - Employment
        - Chicago, Ill., Board of Education, Visual Education Project
          - "Ancient Roman and Byzantine Costume," n.d. (Container 2)
          - "Costume of the Eighteenth Century," n.d. (Container 3) (Box OV 2)
          - Costume of the Middle Ages and seventeenth century, n.d. (Containers 3-5) (Box OV 3)
          - "Egyptian Costume," n.d. (Container 5) (Box OV 4)
        - National Urban League, ca. 1944 (Container 6) (Box OV 5)
      - School papers (Box OV 6)
        - Elementary and high school, 1925, 1932
          - (Container 12)
    - Ellison, Ralph (Box OV 7)
      - Financial papers
        - Income and expenses, 1965-1966, 1973-1980
          - (Containers 21-22)
      - Household papers (Box OV 8)
        - Inventories and insurance, ca. 1968 (Container 24)
        - Key West, Fla. (Box OV 9)
          - Financial papers, 1976-1979 (Container 25)
          - Legal papers, 1976 (Container 25) (Box OV 10)
          - Miscellany, n.d. (Container 26) (Box OV 11)
        - Plainfield, Mass. (Box OV 12)
          - Inventories and insurance, ca. 1968
            - (Container 26)
      - Printed matter, 1967, 1976, 1983, n.d. (Box OV 13)
        - (Container 31)
      - School papers (Box OV 14)
        - Tuskegee Institute, Tuskegee, Ala.
          - Music, 1923, n.d. (Containers 32-33)
          - Publications, 1934-1935 (Container 33) (Box OV 15)
  - General Correspondence (Box OV 16)
    - Ellington, Duke, n.d. (Container 46)
    - Ralph Ellison Branch, Metropolitan Library System, Oklahoma City, Okla. (Box OV 17)
      - Architectural drawings, 1973 (Container 65)
  - Writings (Box OV 18)
    - Miscellany
      - Royalty statements, 1972-1992 (Container 114)
    - Novels
      - Invisible Man
        - Author's first proof, 1951 (Container 152)
        - Published editions
          - Random House
            - Royalties, 1952-1963, 1970-1980
              - (Container 154)
    - Short stories (Box OV 19)
      - "Hymie's Bull" (posthumous title), n.d.
        - (Container 163)
  - Reference File (Box OV 20)
    - Africa, 1953, 1959 (Container 179)
    - African-American studies, 1969 (Container 179)
    - American Indians, 1971 (Container 179)
    - Biographical information
      - Hemingway, Ernest, 1935 (Container 187)
      - Holiday, Billie, 1991 (Container 188)
    - Europe, 1954 (Container 201)
    - Photography, 1937, n.d. (Container 207)
  - Miscellany (Box OV 21)
    - Appointment calendars, 1963, 1991-1993 (Container 213)
    - Awards, citations, and honorary degrees (Box OV 22)
      - College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, Va., 1972 (Container 214)
      - University of Maryland, College Park, Md., 1974 (Container 214)
      - Wake Forest University, Winston-Salem, N.C., 1974 (Container 214)